

703 717 3325 thmsweaver@gmail.com http://thmsweaver.github.io/

#### **SUMMARY:**

Tenacious and globally-minded web developer drawn to causes that benefit the world and human experience. My desire to understand spurs constant self-growth, leading to demonstrated success in tackling difficult endeavors. Thriving on the input of others, the pride I take in the product of group and individual projects requires I maintain a high level of personal accountability.

# **EDUCATION**

General Assembly, Washington, DC, April - July 2014 Web Development Immersive

• Full-stack web development program focused on common best practices in object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test-driven development. Assembled a portfolio of individual and collaborative projects.

## AMIDEAST, Rabat, Morocco, Fall 2012

Area & Arabic Language Studies

- Completed internship with Moroccan NGO in which I helped translate the organization's website from Arabic to English.
- Volunteered teaching English at local elementary and upper schools.

#### Georgetown University, School of Foreign Service, Washington, DC, Summer 2012

Intensive Arabic

 Took advantage of the course's cultural – linguistic exchange component with native speakers in preparation for my semester abroad experience in Morocco.

### Colorado College, Colorado Springs, CO, 2009-2013

Bachelor of Arts with Distinction in Classics and Arabic

- Studied the liberal arts in-depth via an immersive classroom setting while gaining a deep appreciation for the outdoors. I came to love this alternative means of education in which incredible focus was key.
- Phi Sigma Iota International Foreign Language Honor Society

**SKILLS:** Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, jQuery + AJAX, Databases and APIs, Backbone, TDD (Rspec, Jasmine, Capybara), HTML/CSS, Postgresql, Git/Github, Heroku, Agile Development/Scrumming with a team

# **EXPERIENCE**

# International Republican Institute, Washington, DC, June 2013 – April 2014 Afghanistan/Pakistan Programs Assistant & Middle East/North Africa Intern

Provided support for multiple programs based in Pakistan and Afghanistan that engaged political parties from the opposition and government. Programs were carried out by field visits, resident field staff, and contracted consultants; and focused on internal democracy, strategic communications, and issue-based policy development.

- Logistical arrangements and scheduling travel for a five-member delegation of current and former Pakistani
  parliamentarians to and from Pakistan. Planned and scheduled federal, state, and local level meetings in both Washington,
  DC and Los Angeles, CA.
- Helped finalize a public opinion survey delivered to Syrian opposition leaders, tracking in-country political processes.

#### Colorado College Bicycle Cooperative, Colorado Springs, CO, October 2011 - May 2013

Co-Chair

- Created eight new student jobs, expanded inventory and assets after securing funding from the school.
- Reviewed applications, sourced, interviewed, and hired new mechanics from the student body.

### Colorado College Student Farm, Colorado Springs, CO, May 2011 – May 2013

Intern and Co-Chair

- Managed all aspects of a farm providing regular meals for summer classes of over two hundred students.
- Brought the internship under umbrella of related academic departments allowing future interns to receive academic credit.